<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Nebula Graph - An Open Source, Distributed and High Performant Graph Database</title><link>vesoft-inc.github.io/nebula-website/en/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Nebula Graph - An Open Source, Distributed and High Performant Graph Database</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="vesoft-inc.github.io/nebula-website/en/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nebula Contributor | How to Be a GitHub Contributor in Five Minutes</title><link>vesoft-inc.github.io/nebula-website/en/posts/how-to-be-a-github-contributor-in-five-minutes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>vesoft-inc.github.io/nebula-website/en/posts/how-to-be-a-github-contributor-in-five-minutes/</guid><description>Contribute to your first open source project in just five minutes with the help of Nebula Graph.
Preface If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a GitHub account, or aren&amp;rsquo;t sure what Git is, please refer to the official website first.
How to Be a GitHub Contributor Fork Fork the Nebula Graph repo by clicking on the fork button on the top of the main page. This will create a copy of this repository in your account.</description></item><item><title>Being on Hacker News Front Page Brought Us Much More than Just 300+ Stars on GitHub within 24 hours</title><link>vesoft-inc.github.io/nebula-website/en/posts/nebula-graph-being-on-hacker-new-front-page/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>vesoft-inc.github.io/nebula-website/en/posts/nebula-graph-being-on-hacker-new-front-page/</guid><description>Hacker News is said to be the Holy Grail for tech folks. There&amp;rsquo;s one thing that a company, startups in particular, wants desparately: RIGHT traffic for free.
I have never imagined that we would really make it to the front page, especially when I am actually a new comer to the community.
So what happened? On Jan.15, 2020, I saw a submission on the front page titled &amp;ldquo;Thank HN: You helped me get a new job&amp;rdquo; and thought it was great.</description></item><item><title>Nebula Graph in 2019: It’s Worth the Effort</title><link>vesoft-inc.github.io/nebula-website/en/posts/nebula-graph-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>vesoft-inc.github.io/nebula-website/en/posts/nebula-graph-in-2019/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of a year when everyone is checking if their New Year Resolutions for 2019 have been met.
So do we.
In 2019, we have done a lot. And there&amp;rsquo;s also a lot that needs to be done down the road.
Looking back, we are thrilled that Nebula Graph has been shipped to so many graph enthusiatists and pinoneer companies who are always seeking for cutting edge technologies for better business outcomes.</description></item></channel></rss>