<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>query-language on Nebula Graph - An Open Source, Distributed and High Performant Graph Database</title><link>/nebula-website/en/tags/query-language/</link><description>Recent content in query-language on Nebula Graph - An Open Source, Distributed and High Performant Graph Database</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/nebula-website/en/tags/query-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Review on Graph Database</title><link>/nebula-website/en/posts/review-on-graph-databases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nebula-website/en/posts/review-on-graph-databases/</guid><description>This post will discuss the ideas and considerations behind graph databases such as their use cases, advantages and the trends behind this database model with several real-world case example.
A Social Network Scenario Considering a social network scenario shown below, User can post, share their tweets or comment on other people or advertisers&amp;rsquo; tweets, follow each other. It is essential for a data-driven company to use basic CRUD(Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations to add more people, add new messages to the current database or find associated information, help company to figure out certain user&amp;rsquo;s User portrait just like Jeff has many posts relating to AI and music thus we may suppose him a programmer etc.</description></item><item><title>Graph Query Language Comparison Series - Gremlin vs Cypher vs nGQL</title><link>/nebula-website/en/posts/graph-query-language-comparison-cypher-gremlin-ngql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nebula-website/en/posts/graph-query-language-comparison-cypher-gremlin-ngql/</guid><description>In September 2019, Graph Query Language is accepted as a new database query language in a vote by the International SQL Standards Committee, the unification of GQL takes time. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ve selected some mainstream graph query languages and compared the CRUD usage in these languages respectively.
Which Graph Query Languages to Be Compared Gremlin Gremlin is a graph traversal language developed by Apache TinkerPop and has been adopted by a lot of graph database solutions.</description></item></channel></rss>