<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Release-Notes on Nebula Graph - An Open Source, Distributed and High Performant Graph Database</title><link>https://nebula-graph.io/en/tags/release-notes/</link><description>Recent content in Release-Notes on Nebula Graph - An Open Source, Distributed and High Performant Graph Database</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nebula-graph.io/en/tags/release-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nebula Graph RC3 Release Note</title><link>https://nebula-graph.io/en/posts/nebula-graph-rc3-release-note/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nebula-graph.io/en/posts/nebula-graph-rc3-release-note/</guid><description>Main features and fixes for this release include dump_tools to export data by specific filters, graph data exploring tool Nebula Graph Studio, and vertex/edge scan interface for OLAP scenarios. Below is a list of details.
Query engine Support fetching all props of a given vertex #1486 Support DELETE EDGE to delete the given edge #1063 Add IF EXISTS to conditionally drop a tag/edgetype only if it exists. #1505 Add IF NOT EXISTS to conditionally create a space/tag/edge only if it not exists #1379 Export graphd metrics #1451 Storage Add scan edge/vertex interface to retrieve data from storage for OLAP, #1381 Support heartbeat_interval_secs option to config heartbeat interval between storage/graph and meta #1540 Pushdown filter to minimize data transfer and improve query performance #947 Support local conf mode, using local conf rather than config in meta server #1411 Add timeout for storage/meta clients, the default value is 60s and configured by meta_client_timeout_ms option #1399 Support creating a snapshot for the whole cluster #1199 #1372 Both support reading from leader/follow and support only read from the leader #1363 Add check step for each balance task during balancing process.</description></item><item><title>Nebula Graph RC2 Release Note</title><link>https://nebula-graph.io/en/posts/nebula-graph-rc2-release-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nebula-graph.io/en/posts/nebula-graph-rc2-release-note/</guid><description>In our RC2 version, we have made several improvements re the nGQL query language, our Storage Engine, CSV Importer, as well as added Java, Python, and Go Clients.
Below is a detailed rundown of the newly added features:
Query engine Support GROUP BY to group items that have the same values, often used with aggregate functions (COUNT, MAX, MIN, SUM, AVG, etc.) to group the result-set by one or more property field.</description></item></channel></rss>